A Guide to the George E. Uhlenbeck papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA125
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reprints of Contemporary Physicists, 1934-1966, undated; 7; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  - "Some Questions About Quantum Statistical Mechanics", Physica Norvegica. vol. 5, 139-144, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - "Theory of Sound Propagation in Mixtures of Monoatomic Gases" (with J. D. Foch and M. Fuentes Losa), Physics of Fluids. vol. 15, 1224-1232, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - "Possible Origin of the Quantized Vortices in He II" (with S. Putterman and M. Kac), Physical Review Letters, vol. 29, 546-549, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - "Problems of Statistical Physics", in 'The Physicists Concept of Nature'. D. Reidel Pub. Co., Dordrecht, Holland. 501-513, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - "Some Problems In the Kinetic Theory of Dilute Gases", Rarified Gas Dynamics, Academic Press Inc., 3-18, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - "Fifty Years of Spin: Personal Reminiscences", Physics Today, vol. 29, no. 6, 43-48, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - "Some Notes on the Relation Between Fluid Mechanics and Statistical Physics", Review of Fluid Mechanics, vol. 12, 1-9, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - "The Classical Theories of Critical Phenomena", Critical Phenomena, NBS Miscellaneous Pub., 273, 3-6, undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Fundamental Problems in Statistical Mechanics. II. An Outline of Statistical Mechanics, 1-29, undated (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - "Over den Samenhang van Verschillende Oplossingsmethoden der Golfvergelijking in Meerdimensionale Ruimten" (with P. Ehrentest), Koninklijke Akademie van Wetenschappen te Amsterdam. Afdeeling Natuurkunde, [in Dutch], Deel XXXV, No. 4, 1-6, undated (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Some Aspects of Kinetic Theory, 197-207, undated (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Some Historical and Critical Remarks About the Theory of Phase Transitions, 99-107, undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Bethe, H(ans) and Teller E(dward). Deviations from Thermal Equilibrium in Shock Waves, University of Michigan, 1-77, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Bogoliubov, N. "Problems of a Dynamic Theory in Statistical Physics", U.S. Airforce, n.p., 1959 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Carter, Charles. "On the Van der Waals Theory of Binary Mixtures", Phd. Thesis, Rockefeller University, 1-126, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Casimir, H. B. G. "Low Temperature Physics", University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1-60, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Dirac, P. A. M., Dynamic Theory of Fields Classical and Quantum, Lecture Series, University of British Columbia, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Gyson, Freeman. Recent Developments in Quantum Electrodynamics. Lecture Notes, University of Michigan, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Feynman, R(ichard). A New Approach to Quantum Electrodynamics, Notes by M. Fuchs and R. J. Riddell, Jr., University of Michigan, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Feynman, R(ichard). "Quantum Electrodynamics and Meson Theories", University of Michigan, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Furry, W. H. and Oppenheimer, J. R(obert). "On the Theory of the Electron and Positive", Physical Review, vol. 45, 245-262, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Kac, M. On the Theory of Random Noise and Related Problems in Statistical Physics, 1-22 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Oppenheimer, J. R. Notes on Electrodynamics, Notes on his course Physics 207B by S. Kusaka and S. Frankel, University of Calif., 1-70, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Oppenheimer, J. R. Notes on Electrodynamics, Notes on his course Physics 207B by S. Kusaka and S. Frankel, University of Calif., (pp.) 71-148, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Oppenheimer, J. R. Speech Delivered in Honor of Einstein at UNESCO House, Paris, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Klein, O., Lecture Notes on the Relativity Theory For a Book in Progress, 2 pages of formulas in front [possibly Uhlenbeck's notes]. (1 of 3), Brandeis University, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Klein, O., Lecture Notes on the Relativity Theory For a Book in Progress, 2 pages of formulas in front [possible Uhlehbeck's notes]. (2 of 3), Brandeis University, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Klein, O., Lecture Notes on the Relativity Theory For a Book in Progress, 2 pages of formulas in front [possible Uhlehbeck's notes]. (3 of 3), Brandeis University, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Pais, A., Problems in the Theory of Elementary Particles, Notes by Dr. C. S. W. Chang, University of Michigan, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Schwinger, J., Quantum Dynamics Lectures, (1 of 3) University of Calif, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Schwinger, J., Quantum Dynamics Lectures, (2 of 3) University of Calif., (1948). [Also has Pauli's letter on these lectures] (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Schwinger, J., Quantum Dynamics Lectures, (3 of 3) University of Calif., (1948). [Also has Pauli's letter on these lectures] (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Seitz, F., Notes on Summer Lecture: Topics in the Theory of Solids, 1-64, University of Michigan, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Wang Chany, On the Dispersion of Sound in Helium, 1-13, University of Michigan, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Wheeler, Nuclear Physics, notes by Feynman, Notes by Wheeler on Fermi's Cosmic Rays 1-76, Princeton University, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Wigner, E., Notes: On Nuclear Structure and Beta Theory, University of Wisconsin, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 11)